Julia Johnson | Support Engineer

julialj95@gmail.com | 651-491-0926 | Saint Paul, MN LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

SUMMARY

As a customer support engineer and developer with two years of experience in healthcare interoperability support, I have become an adaptable problem solver and a strong collaborator. I am passionate about improving patient healthcare outcomes by helping customers solve their biggest problem in sight.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript ES6, React, React Hooks, jQuery, HTML5, CSS

Back-End: Node.js, PostgreSQL, Express.js, SQL

Additional: Git, Github, RESTful APIs

EXPERIENCE

Tier II Platform Support Engineer | Redox

Aug 2021 - Present

- Provide high quality, empathy-driven technical support to help customers maintain and expand their production integrations
- Function as primary technical resource for platform support team members
- Educate customers and HCOs on healthcare integration
- Develop and maintain an escalation process for Redox's scaling support team

ESL Teacher | VIPKID (Virtual)

Nov 2018 - Aug 2021

- Demonstrate excellent interpersonal skills while facilitating over 3000 one-on-one virtual English lessons with Chinese students between the ages of 3 and 16
- Provide clear and effective written feedback to each student after every lesson
- Conduct monthly progress evaluations and provide detailed feedback to parents and students

Chiropractic Assistant | Clear Health Chiropractic (St. Louis Park, MN)

Dec 2017 - Nov 2018

- Led personalized educational consultations with 10-15 new patients per week
- Wrote and designed office promotional materials and weekly newsletters
- Managed detailed patient records and financial paperwork in a practice with over 300 patients

Seed Regenerator | Seed Savers Exchange (Decorah, IA)

May 2017 - Dec 2017

- Displayed outstanding work ethic and a strong focus on teamwork while taking care of 6 gardens of heritage seed varieties
- Maintained detailed and organized seed and garden records for over 150 varieties of heritage seeds

Franchise Manager | College Pro Painters (Minneapolis, MN)

Jan 2015 - Dec 2015

- Ran a 71k house painting business
- Led two teams of three painters to paint 36 houses with 100% satisfaction ratings
- Found and contracted with all clients independently

EDUCATION

Certificate, Software Engineering | *Thinkful (Online)*

Oct 2020 - April 2021

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards
- Honed skills in React.js, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, HTML5, JavaScript ES6, jQuery, algorithms & data structures
- Participated in mentorship program with industry professionals

Bachelor of Arts in International Studies and Norwegian Language Studies | Music Minor Luther College | Decorah, IA | 2013-2017

• Cumulative GPA of 3.53; named to Dean's List 4 times